

Contact

Email: lbsa71@hotmail.com Phone: +46-733 75 11 99

Languages

English: Native or bilingual proficiency Swedish: Native or bilingual proficiency

Links

https://hiberworld.com/u/Stefan https://soundcloud.com/lbsa71

Stefan Andersson

Jack of all IT trades, master of quite a few

Professional Summary

With 35+ years of experience across many tech stacks and organizational levels, Stefan has become a founder's Swiss army knife - a one-man matrix organization. His versatility spans strategic vision to tactical execution, making him the ideal cornerstone hire for ambitious initiatives and emerging ventures

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer (Apr 2024 - Dec 2024)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden I was part of developing https://hiber3d.com/ Game Studio, SDK, tool chain, backend services and example apps; as a senior resource I coded, created full-stack 3D Web game demos in React and C++, tested, deployed and maintained the entire Hiber3D offer from a technical angle.

Systems Administrator (Oct 2020 - Dec 2024)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden As their CTO I took a hands-on approach to make sure that IT systems were properly managed, managing onboarding/ offboarding, billing, cost and securing their systems. When I stepped aside, I offered to continue the admin role to offload my successor. I also functioned as the main resource for security policy and training.

Key Skills: Security • DevOps • Configuration Management • Infrastructure as code (IaC)

Al Software Developer (Jun 2023 - Apr 2024)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden
As lead for the Hiber Al Research initiative I led the effort to

build and host various large and small multimodal generative Al toolchains. I got to work with a plethora of third-party APIs as well as training, deploying and managing models on GCP Compute and Vertex AI

React / TypeScript Developer (Oct 2022 - Oct 2023)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden
As a member of the Platform team I worked as a full stack
developer; IAC, DevOps, CI, CD, Databases, Backends,
Frontend, Multiple Build Chains, Package Management,
Automatic testing.

Key Skills: React • TypeScript • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • DevOps • Full-Stack Development • Web Development

Information Security | Test Automation Lead (Jan 2022 - Jul 2022)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden In this period Hiber did a push to formalize their security compliance and test automation policy. I was the lead for both these projects, making sure to always properly manage risk and cost.

Key Skills: Security • Test Automation • Software Development • DevOps

Chief Technology Officer (Oct 2020 - Dec 2021)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden Hiber is a venture-backed startup with headquarters in Gothenburg, Sweden, focused on building a social platform for anyone to communicate and express themselves through game-like experiences. As their CTO I organised technology and four agile teams to deliver success while growing.

Key Skills: Team Leadership • Software Architecture • Product Management • Business Strategy • Agile Methodologies • Scrum

CISO | Product Owner | Business Analyst | CloudOps Engineer | Systems Developer (Apr 2018 - Oct 2020)

Allevi AB | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden Allevi AB is the premium provider of time management for LSS, HVB and LOV care providers in Sweden. The company

is highly driven by humane values and implements an 'making a difference' ethos supporting independent living. As their CISO, I made sure they and their customers were kept safe and as a CloudOps engineer I made sure they could deliver highly available systems cost effectively.

Senior Software Developer at Saab (Apr 2017 - Mar 2018)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden

I helped the Secure Transportation team develop the Track and Trace product suite that provide customers with a secure logistic solution for different kinds of transportation. With this solution a user can gain full control over their logistic services through a work-order based system that manages, monitors and measures all services provided for the end customer. The system also creates an operational audit trail from commitment start to final execution, which facilitates having full control throughout the entire transport logistics chain.

Senior Technical Consultant (Feb 2016 - Mar 2018)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden

What attracted me with the young consultancy firm Acorn was that they are committed to nurture a culture in which capable individuals can grow. The decision to leave did not come easy, and I recommend them whole-heartedly both as employers and as suppliers of .NET, Java and embedded software development talent.

Lead Developer at Aros Electronics AB (Feb 2017 - Mar 2017)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden

I was brought in to help Aros bootstrap development of the control system for testing and programming stations in their automated circuit board production facility. The assignment also consisted of coaching the inhouse developers on modern .NET development practices and Software

Architecture.

Senior Developer Team Lead at KGH Customs Services (Feb 2016 - Jan 2017)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden

KGH Customs services is a premiere provider of customs services. Central to these services is the software-as-a-service web based logistics center, integrating KGH, customers and international customs. My role was as Senior Developer and Team Lead for the feature team developing automation of customs declarations, an I also served as the Architect and principal developer for their schema-driven UI Framework.

Senior Software Architect | Senior Software Developer | Lead Tech (Mar 2009 - Feb 2016)

TIBCO Spotfire | Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden

TIBCO Spotfire is the premier studio for enterprise-scale Interactive Visual Analytics. Solutions and Software Architect, Senior Systems Developer and Lead Tech for https://spotfire.cloud.tibco.com/ 1.0.0, 3.0.0-3.3.0 https://silverspotfire.tibco.com/ 2.0-2.7 https://tryspotfire.tibco.com/ 2.0-2.7 Project manager for https://silverspotfire.tibco.com/ 2.0-2.1.1

Co-founder | Lead Programmer (Jan 2007 - Oct 2009) OpenSim |

The OpenSimulator Project is a BSD Licensed Virtual Worlds Server which can be used for creating and deploying 3D Virtual Environments. Fun fact: the platform is mentioned in David Chalmers "Reality+"

CEO (Apr 2007 - Mar 2009)

Tribal Media AB |

Tribal Media AB created high quality high technology interactive 3D mass media solutions.

Lead Programmer (Aug 2004 - Apr 2007)

Playahead AB |

Playahead was Swedens second largest youth web community.

CTO (May 2001 - Jun 2003)

Voice Workers AB |

Voice Workers produced speech recognition and natural dialogue management solutions for telephony.

CTO | Senior consultant (Apr 2000 - Mar 2001)

Ullman Human Design Group AB |

I helped bring the 'Ullman Mouse' into existence by choosing their USB controller and coding assembler for it.

Lead Programmer | Software Architect | Key Account Manager (Apr 1998 - Dec 1999)

Framfab |

Framfab was the second largest web consultancy in Sweden.

Notable Projects

TIBCO Spotfire® Cloud 1.0.0 (Aug 2012 - Present)

TIBCO Spotfire® Cloud is a new set of cloud services for enterprises, work groups, and personal use. TIBCO Spotfire® Cloud Enterprise provides a secure full-featured version of Spotfire in the cloud to analyze and collaborate on business insights, whether or not the data is hosted. For project teams seeking data discovery as a service, TIBCO Spotfire® Cloud Work Group provides a wealth of application-building tools so distributed teams can visually explore data quickly and easily and deploy analytic applications at a very low cost. For individuals looking for a single step to actionable insight, TIBCO Spotfire® Personal is a cost-effective web-based client for quick data discovery needs.

TIBCO Spotfire® Cloud 3.0.0 (Aug 2014 - Dec 2014)

Zero Audience (Aug 2019 - Present)

Zero Audience is a pop-up DJ collective, bringing music to the public space by making bystanders participants.

Education

University of Gothenburg

Bachelor of Science 1996 - 2015

I started my IT studies in 1996, got swept up by the web and finally made it back to take my degree 20 years later.

University of Gothenburg

Courses 1995 - 1996

I took one year of intermediate psychology studies which gave me valuable insights about myself, the work I do, and the world I live in.

Dale Carnegie

2012 - 2013

Course in Communication and Leadership

Technical Skills

Languages

Configuration Management • Full-Stack Development •
Infrastructure as code (IaC) • Product Management • React •
Scrum • Security • Software Architecture • TypeScript

Cloud Infrastructure

DevOps

Core Competencies

Software Development • Web Development

Development Tools

Test Automation

Management

Agile Methodologies • Business Strategy • Team Leadership